## **Enrique Del Castillo Chávez**

GitHub: https://github.com/Enrique246 Email: ecch9210@gmail.com

City/State: Guadalajara, Jalisco

**Zip Code**: 44510 LinkedIn:www.linkedin.com/in/edelcastillo Cel: 333-508-7819

## Summary

Full-stack web developer recently certified by Tec de Monterrey, web and app design oriented with a 7 year administrative career that includes a masters and bachelor's degree in the same field. Digital marketing strategist and administrative manager, with problem solving and decision taking key skills to fulfill personal and professional goals. Teamplayer, bringing a constant positive attitude and a strong work ethic, focused on planning and delivering results. Successfully finding innovative ways to make designs come to life.

#### **Technical Skills**

• Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Foundation, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Local Storage, Session Storage, Node.js, JSON, Express, Herokou, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Local Storage, Session Storage, IndexedDB, React.js.

## **Projects**

My Book Cloud https://github.com/Enrique246/project1-mybookcloud https://enrique246.github.io/project1-mybookcloud/

- App where you can search in Google Books & New York Times best-sellers API's
- Project manager, responsible for team progress, delivery and the proper functionality of the New York Times app search engine.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JQuery, Foundation, API, JSON, Local-Storage

## Yoga Studio | https://github.com/Enrique246/yoga-project |

https://damp-dawn-28515.herokuapp.com

- App dedicated to description of yoga classes and reservation.
- Back-end focus responsibility. (API routing & Modeling)
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap, API, JSON, Local-Storage, MySQL, Handlebars, Heroku deployment, Sequelize, Node.js, Bcrypt, Express, EsLint.

## **Work Experience**

### **Private Dental Office**

01/2019 to 06/2021

## **Administrative Manager**

Guadalajara, Mexico

- Brand development with a 100% of client satisfaction.
- Business digitalization, achieving change in software suppliers increasing administrative department effectiveness up to 80%.
- Building of employee position manuals, lowering in 50% employee training.

New team hiring, climbing 50% in work efficiency and quality.

Randstad (International Recruitment Agency)

04/2018 to 09/2018

#### Staffing Consultant

Vancouver, Canada

Negotiation with clients and candidates with 50% of increase in candidate recruitment.

- Strong background check skills of candidates reducing in 60% candidate drop out.
- In a massive recruitment of 200 positions, successfully fulfilled 20 of them within a month.

#### **Education**

## **Full Stack Flex Web Development Certificate**

Aug 2021

Tecnológico de Monterrey Campus Guadalajara

Guadalajara, Mexico

A high-paced 24-week course, establishing technical program skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, JSON, AJAX, Java, MySQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Unit Testing, Functional Testing, Linting, Continuous Integration, Express, User Authentication, Progressive Web Applications (PWAs), MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), Responsive Design Bootstrap Handlebars, Local Storage, Session Storage, IndexedDB React.js

#### **Master in Business Management**

**Dec 2020** 

Tecnológico de Monterrey Campus Guadalajara

Guadalajara, Mexico

• Intensive 1 year program focused on innovation and corporate entrepreneurship. Including a high amount of case studies, Python, technology, design, emotional intelligence and a real-life practicum.

# Post-Service System Design | Research Project | Master's degree practicum (Jan 2020 - Sept 2020) | Urrea: Tecnología para Vivir el Agua

- Generate maturity diagnosis, identify process opportunity areas, develop impact proposals with a customer centricity focus and its digitalization.
- Project leader, responsible for assuring objectives where being done and designing the training system.
- Tools: Canva, Google Drive, Science Direct, Sales Force.

## **BBA Business Administration and Human Resources**

Dec 2016

Universidad Panamericana de Guadalajara

Guadalajara, Mexico

• Business bachelor's degree with emphasis in talent management. Including legal, accounting and policy organization building.